Guide to the Margaret Hodges Papers, 1911-2006 SC.1990.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Articles, 1923-1985; V.
  - Published Articles, 1.
    - City Slicker -Junior League Lights, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Dear Old Shadyside -Junior League Lights, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Overheard at a Talent Party -Junior League Lights, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Carte Blanche -Junior League Lights, 1952-1953 (Box 16, Folder 10-14)
    - Top of the News, A Book to Remember -Horn Book, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Top of the News, Happy Birthday! The Wind in the Willows -Horn Book, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Top of the News, The Wilder Nominees -Horn Book, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Top of the News, They Also Serve -Horn Book, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Opening the Door -Carnegie Magazine, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Fine Arts Enrich Preschoolers -The Division of Compensatory Education's Portrait of a Preschool, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Review of Professional Literature. The Rise of Children's Book Reviewing in America 1865-1881 -Drexel Library Quarterly, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Storytelling in the Pre-Primary Program -Pittsburgh Public Schools Curriculum Bulletin, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Telling Stories to Young Children -Instructor, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Horn Book -The Encyclopedia of Library and Information Science, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Your Living Child, M. Flemming -Horn Book, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 25-26)
    - A Laying of Hands -Catholic Library World, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - After Folktales-What? -New England Reading Association Journal, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Newbery and Caldecott Books 1966-1975, With Acceptance Papers, Biographies and Related Material -Horn Book (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - A Second Look: The Tailor of Gloucester -Horn Book, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 30-32)
    - Research Collections in College and University Libraries -Library Trends, 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 1-6)
    - The American Children of RLS -Horn Book, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
    - Storytelling -The Encyclopedia of Library and Information Science, 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Katharine Briggs: A Memoir -Children's Literature in Education, 1977-1985 (Box 17, Folder 10-12)
    - Dickens for Children -Horn Book, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 13-15)
    - Preface -Kenneth Grahame's The Wind in the Willows 75th Anniversary Ed, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - The Talking Fish -Count Down School Magazine, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - The Talking Fish -Cricket, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - The Hereditary Profession -CLPpings, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Vassar Author: Lost and Found -Vassar Quarterly, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Elizabeth Nesbitt -Dictionary of American Library Biography, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Asbjornsen & Moe 1812-1885 and 1813-1882 -Writers for Children, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - J.M. Barrie 1860-1937 -Writers for Children, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Robert Louis Stevenson 1850-1894 -Writers for Children, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - When Robert Louis Stevenson Was One of Us -American Heritage, 1973-1992 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
    - The Classics: Bring Them Back Alive -Catholic Library World, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Three Friends -Cricket, 1989-1992 (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
    - East Meets West in Lafcadio Hearn -Japanese Association of Greater Pittsburgh Newsletter, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 7-9)
    - Published Editorials, 1978-1984 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - 40th Anniversary Retrospective -SLJ, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Unpublished Articles, 1974-1985; 2.
    - A Litel Clergeoun -Children's Literature, Typescript, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Ourselves and Our Daily Tasks -Soundings, Typescript, Class Paper for Religion 214, 1982-1984 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Clifton Fadiman: A Portrait of C -Columbia College Today, Manuscript and Typescript, 1974-1985 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Children's Books, 1960-2006; VI.
  Manuscripts and typescripts of Hodges' books, as well as research, publication correspondance, art, reviews and promotional materials.
  - One Little Drum, 1970-1978; 1.
    Published in 1958 by Follet Pub. Co.
    - Fan Mail, 1973-1978 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Photograph, Newspaper Articles, and Book Jacket, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - What's for Lunch, Charley?, 1961-1978; 2.
    Published in 1961 by Scholastic Book Services.
    - Fan Mail, 1971-1978 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper Article and Book Jacket, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - A Club Against Keats, 1962-1971; 3.
    Published in 1962 by Dial Press.
    - Fan Mail, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Promotional Materials and Articles, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Tell It Again, Great Tales From Around the World, 1963; 4.
    Published in 1963 by Dial Press.
    - Review and Book Jacket (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - The Secret in the Woods, 1964; 5.
    1964
    - Reviews and Book Jacket (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - The Wave, 1963-1997; 6.
    Published in 1964 by Houghton Miflin Co.
    - Research, 1985-1991 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Contracts, Royalty Statements, Requests for Permission to Reproduce, 1963-1995 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence to Hodges, 1989-1997 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence From Hodges, 1970-1995 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Typescript and Edited Copy of the Book (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Photocopy of the Book With Changed Copyright Statement (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence From Illustrator, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Reviews, 1964-1970 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Fan Mail, 1971-1990 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Promotional Materials and Study Guide, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - The Hatching of Joshua Cobb, 1967-1979; 7.
    Published in 1967 by Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Fan Mail, Articles and Reviews (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Constellation: A Shakespeare Anthology, 1968-1979; 8.
    Published in 1968 by Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Typescripts
      - Title Page, Forward, and Table of Contents, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Anthony and Cleopatra (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - As You Like It (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Cymbeline (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Hamlet (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Julius Caesar (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - King Henry IV (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - King Henry V (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - King John (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - King Lear (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - King Richard II (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - King Richard III (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Love's Labor's Lost (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Macbeth (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Measure for Measure (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - The Merchant of Venice (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - A Midsummer Night's Dream (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Othello (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Romeo and Juliet (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - The Taming of the Shrew (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - The Tempest (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Timon of Athens (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Troilus and Cressida (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Twelfth Night (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - The Two Gentlemen of Verona (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - The Winter's Tale (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - Guide to Famous Lines and Phrases (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Publication Materials and Fanmail
      - Layout Drawings With Notes From Publisher (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - Dust Jacket (Box 19, Folder 29)
      - Reviews, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 30)
      - Fan Mail, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Sing Out, Charley!, 1968-1977; 9.
    - Reviews, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Fan Mail, 1971-1977 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Derivatives, School Play, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Lady Queen Anne: A Biography of Queen Anne of England, 1969-1972; 10.
    Published in 1969 by Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Typescript (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Reviews, 1969-1972 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence About Book, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Research Index Cards (Box 20, Carton 1)
  - The Making of Joshua Cobb, 1971-1974; 11.
    Published in 1971 by Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Dust Jacket (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Reviews, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Fan Mail, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - The Fire Bringer: A Paiute Indian Legend, 1972-1978; 12.
    Published in 1972 by Little, Brown and Co.
    - Dust Jacket (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Book Reviews, 1972-1978 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Fan Mail, 1974-1977 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Other Publications of the Story, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - The Gorgon's Head: A Myth From the Isles of Greece, 1972-1981; 13.
    - Dust Jacket (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Reviews, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Hopkins of the Mayflower: Portrait of a Dissenter, 1972-1992; 14.
    Published in 1972 by Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Research and Correspondence
      - Research (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Research Requests and Correspondence, 1970-1972, 1992-1994 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Reasearch Photographs (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - Research Correspondence With Roger Fulling, 1985-1992 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence to Farrar, Straus, and Giroux (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence From Farrar, Straus, and Giroux (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence With Higginson Books Regarding Reprinting, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Typescripts
      - Typescript 1 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - Typescript 2, Multiple Drafts Recieved Together, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Typescript 3, Author's Note and Chapter I (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - Typescript 3, Chapters II-IV (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - Typescript 3, Chapters V-VI (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - Typescript 3, Chapters VII-IX (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - Typescript 3, Chapter X (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - Typescript 3, Chapter XI (Box 21, Folder 24)
      - Typescript 3, Chapter XII (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Typescript 3, Chapters XIII-XVI (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Typescript 3, Chapter XV (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Typescript 3, Chapter XVI (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Typescript 3, Chapter: Tapestry (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Publication Materials and Fanmail
      - Notes on Hopkins Manuscript by Fletcher Hodges, Jr. (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Bibliography (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Dust Jacket (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Reviews, 1972-1979 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Fan Mail, 1971-1979 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Promotional Materials, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - The Other World: Myths of the Celts, 1973-1975; 15.
    Published in 1973 by Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Research Photographs (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Typescript (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Dust Jacket (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Reviews and Promotional Materials, 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Fan Mail and Correspondence, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Persephone and the Springtime: A Greek Myth, 1973-1991; 16.
    Published in 1973 by Little, Brown and Co.
    - Dust Jacket (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Reviews and Promotional Materials (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Demeter's Lament, Concert in Cherry Hill, NJ, Including VHS Tape and Audio Cassette, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Baldur and the Mistletoe: A Myth of the Vikings, 1973-1974; 17.
    Published in 1974 by Little, Brown and Co.
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Dust Jacket (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Typescript of Retelling (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - The Freewheeling of Joshua Cobb, 1974; 18.
    Published in 1974 by Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Dust Jacket (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Reviews and Promotional Materials (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Fan Mail (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Knight Prisoner: The Tale of Sir Thomas Malory and His King Arthur, 1974-1978; 19.
    Published in 1976 by Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Research, Including Photographs (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Research, Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Dust Jacket (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Reviews and Promotional Materials, 1976-1977 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Audiocassette of Speeches, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 30)
      Includes speeches by Professor Eugene Vinaver (Highland Hotel, Canterbury, England, 10 August 1976) and Dr. Katharine M. Briggs (St. Margaret's Bay, Dover, England) on 11 August 1976,
  - The High Riders, 1979-1982; 20.
    Published in 1980 by Charles Scribner's Sons.
    - Photographs and Research (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence With Editors, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Dust Jacket (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Reviews and Promotional Materials, 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - The Little Humpbacked Horse: A Russian Tale, 1984; 21.
    Published in 1980 by Farrar, Straus and Giroux.
    - Typescript (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence From C. Conover, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Reviews and Promotional Materials, 1980-1984 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - The Avenger, 1979-1983; 22.
    Published in 1982 by Charles Scribner's Sons.
    - Research and Photographs, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence With Publisher, 1981-1983 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Dust Jacket (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Reviews and Promotional Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - If You Had a Horse: Steeds of Myth and Legend, 1984; 23.
    Published in 1984 by Scribner.
    - Adaptation and Typescripts (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Dust Jacket (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - St. George and the Dragon: A Golden Legend, 1970-1995; 24.
    Published in 1984 by Little, Brown and Co.
    - Research Reference Sources, Including Photographs and Flag, 1970-1984 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Page Proof (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Dust Jacket (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence From Trina Schart Hyman, 1983-1990 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Black and White Photographs of Book Illustrations (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Reviews, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Post-Publication Correspondence From Little, Brown & Co., 1984-1990 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Post-Publication Correspondence to Little, Brown & Co., 1984-1990 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence to Hodges, Including Letter From Fred Rogers, 1984-1995 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence From Hodges, 1984-1987 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Communication Log of Hodges, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Promotional Materials (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1984-1990 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Caldecott Announcement and Awards Dinner, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - PLA Carolyn Fields Award, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Other Awards and Appearances, Including Photographs, 1984-1994 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Audiocassette, Collections for Young Scholars, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - The Arrow and the Lamp: The Story of Psyche, 1984-1992; 25.
    Published in 1989 by Little, Brown and Co.
    - Research (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence From Little, Brown & Co., Including Publishing Manual, 1984-1990 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to Little, Brown & Co., 1985-1990 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Typescript 1, With Revisions (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Typescript 2, With Title Page (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Typescript 3 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Typescript 4 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Typescript 5, Final With Publisher and Editor Notes, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Proof and Memo From the Editor (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Galley Proof (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence to Hodges, 1985-1989 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence From Hodges, 1985-1992 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Reviews, 1989-1990 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Derivatives, Without a Map, Including Manuscript and Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Making a Difference: The Story of an American Family, 1980-1997; 26.
    Published in 1989 by Charles Scribner's Sons.
    - Research
      - Family Tree (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Hodges' Notes (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Mary (Box 24, Folder 18-22)
        Folder 19 contains notes on a Photocopy of "Living Recollections" by Mary Abigail Sherwood. Folder 20 contains "Living Recollections" by Mary Abigail Sherwood inscribed by author to M. Hodges.
      - Merriam (Box 24, Folder 23-27)
        Folder 1 includes photographs.
      - Helen (Box 24, Folder 28-29)
      - Jean (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
      - Penelope, Including Photograph (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Sidney, Jr., Including Photograph (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Anna Roosevelt (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
      - Roosevelt Library (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Vassar College Information (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Geographic Information (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - General Information (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Transcription of Conversations With Jean Harper, Hazel Brill Jackson, and Charles Keene, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Audiocassettes
        - Interview With Harnet Donwath, Gertrude Reed, and Eleanor Grier Regarding Vassar College, circa 1914-1918 (Box 25, Cassette 1)
        - Interview With Sidney Sherwood, 1982 (Box 25, Cassette 2-3)
        - Interview With Helen Brill Jackson, 1987 (Box 25, Cassette 4)
        - Interview With Charles Keene About Helen Sherwood, 1987 (Box 25, Cassette 5)
    - Correspondence
      - To Hodges, 1983-1990 (Box 25, Folder 14-15)
      - From Hodges, 1982-1989 (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
      - From David Harper, 1985-1991 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - To David Harper, 1985-1991 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - From Sherwood/Harper Family, 1982-1990 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - To Sherwood/Harper Family, 1980-1989 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - From L. Foster, Including Photographs, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - From Charles Scribner's Sons, 1986-1989 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - To Charles Scribner's Sons, 1986-1990 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Publication Materials
      - Letters of Permission From Harper Family, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Partial Typescript 1, With Notes (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Typescript 2, With Handwritten Notes (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - Index on Note Cards (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Galley Proof 1, With Handwritten Notes, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - Galley Proof 2, With Handwritten Notes, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Galley Proof 3, With Notes and Water Damage, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Reviews, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Promotional Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - The Voice of the Great Bell, 1968-1999; 27.
    - Research (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Research, Hearn Magazine (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence to Hodges, 1968-1999 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence From Hodges, 1968-1989 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Typescript 1, Final With Notes (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Typescript 2, Partial, A Bicentennial Fit for a King (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of Illustrations (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Reviews and Promotional Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - East Meets West Talk and Derivitives, Including Slides (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Speech Read by Megan MacDonald for Hodges (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Buried Moon, 1987-1991; 28.
    Published in 1990 by Little, Brown and Co.
    - Research (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence From Little, Brown and Co., 1987-1991 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence to Little, Brown and Co., 1987-1989 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Manuscript (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Typescript 2, Final With Publisher and Editor Notes (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Galley Proof, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof With Dust Jacket (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Photocopy of Illustrations (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Reviews, 1990-1991 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - The Kitchen Knight: A Tale of King Arthur, 1985-1995; 29.
    Published in 1990 by Holiday House.
    - Research, Including Photographs (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence From Holiday House, 1986-1990 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence to Holiday House, 1985-1990 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence to Little, Brown and Co., Typescript Solicitations, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Typescript 3 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Typescript 4, Final With Publisher and Editor Notes (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Galley Proof 1, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Galley Proof 2, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Galley Proof 3, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence From Trina Schart Hyman, 1988-1991 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Paperback Book (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Reviews, 1990-1991 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Promotional Materials, 1990-1995 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Fan Mail, 1985-1991 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Derivatives, Play Adaptation and Programs (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Brother Francis and the Friendly Beasts, 1988-1991; 30.
    Published in 1991 by Charles Scribner's Sons.
    - Research, With Fragile Map (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence From Publishers, 1988-1991 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to Publishers, 1989-1991 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Typescript 3, With Editor's Notes (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Flap Copy Proofs (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Folded and Gathered Proof (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Reviews (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Derivatives, Children's Play for Mr. Rogers' Neighborhood (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Hauntings: Ghosts and Ghouls From Around the World, 1989-1991; 31.
    Published in 1991 by Little, Brown and Co.
    - Research and Correspondence
      - Research (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - Research for Joe Magrac, Including Photographs (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence From Little, Brown and Co., 1989-1991 (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence to Little, Brown and Co., 1989-1991 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence to and From Hodges, 1990-1991 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Outline, Holograph (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Typescripts and Proofs
      - Aunt Tildy's Ghost Story (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - The City at the Bottom of the Sea (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - The Godfather Death (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - The Stone Boat (Box 29, Folder 21)
      - The Coffin Lid (Box 29, Folder 22)
      - The Hungry Witch (Box 29, Folder 23)
      - Tiny Man, Also Contains Manuscript (Box 29, Folder 24)
      - The Bells of Y's (Box 29, Folder 25)
      - The Haunted Harp (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - The Golem, Also Contains Manuscript (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - Lord of Death, Also Contains Manuscript (Box 29, Folder 28)
      - Snow (Box 29, Folder 29)
      - The Bunyip, Also Contains Manuscript (Box 29, Folder 30)
      - Joe Magarac, Also Contains Manuscript (Box 29, Folder 31)
      - Typescript With Editor and Publisher Notes (Box 29, Folder 32)
      - Unused Typescripts and Manuscripts (Box 29, Folder 33)
      - Galley Proof (Box 29, Folder 34)
      - Advanced Proof, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 35)
      - Dust Jacket (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Photocopies of Illustrations (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Reviews, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - St. Jerome and the Lion, 1988-1992; 32.
    Published in 1991 by Orchard Books.
    - Research (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence From Orchard Books, 1989-1992 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence to Orchard Books, 1989-1992 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Manuscript (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Proof (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Reviews (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Promotional Materials, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Don Quixote and Sancho Panza, 1986-1993; 33.
    Published in 1992 by Charles Scribner's Sons.
    - Research, Hodges' Paper, The Looking Glass Game, From English LIterature 261 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence From Publisher, 1987-1993 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence to Publisher, 1986-1992 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Manuscript (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Typescript 1 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Typescript 2 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Typescript 3 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Typescript 4 (Box 30, Folder 21)